I'm at the Google News website.
我现在在谷歌新闻网站上
The Google News website has a nice layout, doesn't it?
谷歌新闻网站有很优秀的布局
For example if I shrink the browser,
比如 如果我缩小浏览器
everything adapts to a smaller screen.
一切都能适应较小的屏幕
All the content is divided into clear sections,
所有内容明确划分
this is all done with CSS styling.
这一切都是 CSS 样式
So, I'm going to show you a little trick where you can
我要展示一个小技巧
actually remove the CSS for a website.
实际上可以删除网站的 CSS
I'm going to open something called developer tools
我要打开一个叫开发者工具的东西
which lets you see the code that makes up a website.
你可以在其中看到构成网站的代码
I'm in Chrome and if you go to the menu bar at the top.
我使用的是 Chrome 如果你找到顶部的菜单栏
It's under view, then developer and finally developer tools.
可以在视图下找到开发者 最后是开发者工具
So, here in this box is the HTML for this website,
这个框中就是该网站的 HTML 了
I'm going to delete the head tag which among
我要删除其中的 head 标签
other things contains code for the CSS styling.
其中包含 CSS 样式的代码以及一些其他东西
Now all we're left with is the HTML of the website,
现在剩下的就是网站的 HTML
if I scroll down you can see that this looks a lot like the HTML code
向下滚动 可以看到这看起来很像
that you've been writing it's just HTML without any style attached to it.
你之前编写的 HTML 代码 这只是 HTML 没有附加任何样式
I wanted to show you this because behind every webpage,
我想展示这个 因为在每个网页的背后
no matter how good the page looks,
无论页面看起来多美观
it's really just HTML holding all of the content.
都只是 HTML 包含所有内容
The styling like the column layout, colors,
像列布局、颜色、字体这样的样式
fonts, all of these are specified using a language called CSS.
都是使用一种叫做 CSS 的语言指定的
CSS stands for Cascading Style Sheets.
CSS 是 Cascading Style Sheets 的缩写 意为层叠样式表
You write CSS code to specify what each element on your page should look like.
你编写 CSS 代码来指定页面上每个元素的外观
I'm going to give you a quick intro to CSS.
我将给出对 CSS 的快速简介
Although to build the actual web app at the end of this lesson,
虽然在本课结束构建实际的 Web 应用时
you'll use a front end library that does the CSS styling for you.
你会使用一个为你设计 CSS 样式的前端库
Here's the webpage that we've been working on.
这是我们之前编辑的网页
There are essentially two different ways to write CSS,
编写 CSS 有两种不同的方法
inline CSS and CSS written in a style sheet.
内联 CSS 和样式表中的 CSS
With inline CSS you specify the style inside a tag using the style attribute.
使用内联 CSS 你可以在标签中使用 style 属性指定样式
For example, to change the first paragraph to a bold font,
例如 要将第一个段落更改为粗体
I would write style equals font weight bold.
我会这样写 style="font-weight:bold;"
So, you can see the syntax here,
可以看到这里的语法
I say what I want to change in this case the font weight,
我声明了我想修改的是什么 在这个例子中是 font-weight
how I want to change it,
我想怎样修改它
I want it to be bold, and then I need to separate those two with a colon,
我希望它的值为 bold 然后我需要用冒号将这两者分开
and then finally I end with a semicolon.
最后以分号结尾
I can add other things here like let's say color red.
我可以在这里添加其他东西 比如假设颜色为红色
So, I'm adding another rule to this paragraph and everything turns red.
那么我就在这个段落中添加了另一个规则 一切都变成了红色
You can do all kinds of things to change the styling,
你可以设置很多不同的值来改变样式
and I'll put some references below the video so that
我会在视频下面放一些参考资料
you can see all the different things you can do.
其中可以看到你能够完成的所有不同操作
I'm going to start adding some more style rules,
我要开始添加更多样式规则
for example here in the body, I'm going to say,
比如对于 body 来说 我要设置为
margin-left 20 pixels, margin right 20 pixels,
外边距左侧 20px 外边距右侧 20px
and let's see what that does.
让我们看看这句代码的作用
So, if you've noticed,
如果你能注意到
it actually squeeze in my content a
这实际上将我的内容挤压了一点
little bit so wasn't flush against the left and right side.
左右两侧不是齐平的了
Let's go down to the image tag here
我们来看看这里的图像标签
and we're going to make the image a little bit smaller.
我们要把图像缩小一点
I'm going to go up to the link here,
然后到这里的链接中
and I'm going to say style text decoration none,
将文字装饰设置为没有
and you can see that it took away this underlying those underneath the link here.
然后你可以看到这里移除了链接的下划线
So, you can add all kinds of different styles.
所以 你可以添加各种不同的样式
For example, what else did I have here.
看看还有什么
This green text here I could style here,
这里的 green_text 类 我可以在这里设置样式
and say color green.
将其颜色设置为绿色
So, you can do all sorts of things.
你可以做各种各样的事情
The problem however with writing CSS this way
然而问题是 以这种方式编写 CSS
is that you have to specify the CSS for each individual tag,
你必须为每个单独的标签指定 CSS
and that's kind of tedious.
这就有些乏味了
It also doesn't totally take advantage of what CSS can
也没有完全利用 CSS 的优势
do which is essentially to separate the content in HTML,
CSS 本质上是为了分离 HTML 中的内容
and make the styling totally separate.
使样式完全分离
I'm going to start over again from scratch with the original HTML,
我将从头开始重新使用原始 HTML
that didn't have any styling.
没有任何样式
So, an alternative way to putting the style is here with the style sheet.
放置样式的另一种方法是使用样式表
So, I go up into the head tag,
进入 head 标签
and I make this new element called style.
我创建了一个名为 style 的新元素
Now I can add CSS rules into the style sheet so that it's
现在我可以将 CSS 规则添加到样式表中
actually separated from the HTML content.
这样就可以实际上与 HTML 内容区分开
The syntax in a style sheet is to first
样式表中的语法 首先要
specify the element type tag or class that you want to style,
指定设置样式的元素类型标签或 class
and then you write out a rule for the style.
然后写出一个样式的规则
For example, if I want to style only the paragraph with the p top ID,
比如 如果我只想设置带有 p_top id 的段落
I specify the p top ID using the pound sign, right up p top,
我使用 # 号 然后后面马上接 p_top 来指定该 id
open squiggly bracket, close squiggly bracket,
打开大括号 关闭大括号
and then I write my style rule inside.
然后在里面编写我的样式规则
In this case I'm going say font, weight bold,
在这个示例中 我要设置为 font-weight:bold;
and you can see now that the first top paragraph has a font-weight bold.
现在可以看到第一个段落的字体加粗了
Let's add some more rules just so you can see what it looks like.
让我们添加更多规则 看到更多规则的样子
OK. What if I want to style the body tag?
好 如果我想要修改 body 标签的样式怎么办
All I have to do here is write body to represent the body tag,
我需要做的只是写下 body 来代表 body 标签
and then have my open and close squiggly brackets,
然后打开和关闭大括号
and then I can specify whatever I want like margin left 20 pixels,
然后我可以指定任何我想要的 外边距左侧 20px
margin right 20 pixels and again that's squeezing all
外边距右侧 20px 再次挤压了所有文本
of the texts all of the content so that it's not flush with the sides anymore.
以及所有内容 不再与边缘齐平
I can add a border,
我可以添加一个边框
maybe add some padding so that everything isn't stuck right on the border.
也许添加一些内边距 这样不会都卡在边框上
So, you can see I'm starting to style all this.
你可以看到我开始设计这一切的样式
I want to style the image so that it's not so large,
我想为图像设置样式 使其不那么大
takeaway those underlines from the links,
在链接中删除那些下划线
and then if you go down to the HTML,
然后如果你去看 HTML
remember I have this class called green text.
记得我有一个叫做 green_text 的 class
So, to add style to a class,
要为一个 class 添加样式
I use this.syntax, and then the name of
需要用 . 语法 然后是 class 的名字
the class and I'm going to change the color to green.
我要把颜色变成绿色
So, you can start to see the advantages of using IDs and classes.
开始能够看到使用 id 和 class 的优势了
For example with the ID on
比如 使用第一段的 id
the first paragraph I was able to just make this first paragraph bold,
我能够只把第一段加粗
and with the green text class I could make just this part green,
使用 green_text 类 我可以使这部分和
and this part green,
这部分都变成绿色
by just using one style rule.
只需设置一个样式规则
Writing the style this way is called an internal style
以这种方式编写样式称为内部样式表
sheet because it's still internal to the HTML document.
因为它仍然是 HTML 文档的内部
To make the code even cleaner and modular,
为了使代码更清晰和模块化
you can put the CSS into a separate file.
你可以把 CSS 放到一个单独的文件中
Now, the last step is to link to the style sheet in the HTML document.
现在 最后一步是在 HTML 文档中链接样式表
You do that with the link tag and here in
你可以使用 link 标签
the h-ref attribute you put the name of the file,
href 属性中输入文件名称
close everything and now you've got your CSS styling.
结束所有内容 现在你已经拥有了 CSS 样式
So, now the content in
所以现在的 HTML 文档内容
the HTML document and the styling in the CSS document are completely separate.
和 CSS 文档中的样式是完全独立的
I want to mention that I know I am showing you a lot of things at a very rapid pace,
再提一下 我知道我是以非常快的速度向你展示很多东西
but the goal is to become proficient not necessarily an expert.
但目标只是熟悉这些内容 而不必成为专家
Soon, I'll present a few tools that make web development somewhat easier,
很快 我将介绍一些使 Web 开发更容易的工具
so that you don't have to know all of these CSS rules.
这样就不必了解所有这些 CSS 规则
But I'm giving you an introduction so that
但我想给出这些介绍
you understand what's happening behind the scenes.
让你了解幕后发生的事情
Next up you'll practice writing CSS and then we'll move on to JavaScript.
接下来你将练习编写 CSS 然后我们将继续学习 JavaScript